<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Darshan Crout</title>
    <link>https://darshancrout.ai/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Darshan Crout</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Darshan Crout</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://darshancrout.ai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating YouTube Titles Using Image Captioning</title>
      <link>https://darshancrout.ai/post/generating-youtube-titles-using-image-captioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darshancrout.ai/post/generating-youtube-titles-using-image-captioning/</guid>
      <description>I watch a lot of YouTube. In fact, a lot of younger people watch more YouTube than they watch television. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, YouTube is not only an endless source of entertainment, but it also serves as a source of knowledge and information. The platform has videos on just about anything from how to make your own fermented food, cracking the Sega Saturn or Joe Rogan interviewing himself. However, if you have been on the platform for as long as I have, you have probably caught on by now just how much clickbait YouTube creators use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Site Using Hugo</title>
      <link>https://darshancrout.ai/post/building-a-site-using-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darshancrout.ai/post/building-a-site-using-hugo/</guid>
      <description>As of late, I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting interested in software philosophies such as the Unix philosophy and Suckless, hoping that they will provide me with some guidance on how to become a better programmer. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been wanting to redo my personal blog for quite some time, but never did because I would always get bogged down on choosing a theme. While browsing for site themes, I came across Simple Hugo Theme which is a Hugo theme inspired by http://bettermotherfuckingwebsite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://darshancrout.ai/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darshancrout.ai/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently a data scientist at Scotiabank based in Toronto, Ontario. I have a MSc in Computer Science and BSc in Physics.
During my undergrad, I got involved in mathematical models for biological aggregation and opinion dynamics in which I solved differential equations using Monte Carlo methods. This got me interested in big data problems in addition to the field of machine learning. Naturally loving math and problem solving, I enrolled in the Professional Master&amp;rsquo;s program in Big Data at Simon Fraser University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://darshancrout.ai/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darshancrout.ai/now/</guid>
      <description>Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to recently!
Books Currently Reading  Our Band Could Be Your Life: Scenes from the American Indie Underground 1981-1991, by Michael Azerrad Thinking, Fast and Slow, by Daniel Kahneman  Projects  [June 1, 2019] Spotitude is now a web app: https://spotitude.me/. Look at your top tracks on different time ranges and create a playlist. Made with Vue.js. Code found here [ May 26, 2019 ] Frustrated about how Spotify doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide their users with their analytics, I created a tool called Spotitude which displays a user&amp;rsquo;s top 25 tracks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>https://darshancrout.ai/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darshancrout.ai/setup/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the gear other people use to get their work done. If you&amp;rsquo;re at all curious, here&amp;rsquo;s my personal setup:
Lenovo ThinkPad x220 The xx20 ThinkPad series is the last one to have the classical keyboard. I use this computer as my daily driver. I run Ubuntu LTS as my primary OS, switching between different window managers. For development I use tmux and Spacemacs. My dotfiles are hosted on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>