<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archives on Darshan Crout</title>
    <link>https://dtcrout.github.io/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archives on Darshan Crout</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 Darshan Crout (&lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/durshmallow&#39;&gt;@durshmallow&lt;/a&gt;). All rights reserved.</copyright><atom:link href="https://dtcrout.github.io/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://dtcrout.github.io/archive/now_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dtcrout.github.io/archive/now_2019/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of things I was up to in 2019.
Reading 📚 Completed Meditations, by Marcus Aurelius Capitalist Realism: Is There No Alternative?, by Mark Fisher The Birth of the Clinic, by Michel Foucault Being and Time (Part I, Division I), by Martin Heidegger White Noise, by Don DeLillo Our Band Could Be Your Life: Scenes from the American Indie Underground 1981-1991, by Michael Azerrad Currently Reading Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus, by Ludwig Wittgenstein On the Road, by Jack Kerouac Existentialism from Dostoevsky to Sartre: Basic Writings of Existentialism by Kaufmann, Kierkegaard, Nietzsche, Jaspers, Heidegger, and Others, by Walter Kaufmann Paper Pile Troubling Trends in Machine Learning Scholarship (2018) Zachary C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://dtcrout.github.io/archive/now_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dtcrout.github.io/archive/now_2020/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of things I was up to in 2020.
Reading 📚 Completed Women, Race and Class, by Angela Davis Big Sur, by Jack Kerouac The Prince, by Niccolò Machiavelli The Dharma Bums, by Jack Kerouac Nineteen Eighty-Four, by George Orwell On the Road, by Jack Kerouac The Old Man and the Sea, by Ernest Hemingway L&amp;rsquo;étranger, by Albert Camus Black Skin, White Masks, by Frantz Fanon Currently Reading Journey to the End of the Night, by Louis-Ferdinand Céline Being and Time, by Martin Heidegger The World as Will and Representation, Vol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
